Mss.B.P31
American Philosophical Society
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1675-1960; 27 boxes, 8.5 linear feet
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Oct. 14, 1851; 10x8; Cornwell, George
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks for payment of draft.
  - Letter to [Ann Sellers], Oct. 26, 1851; 10x8; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p.with P.S.by Anna Sellers of 3p. Family news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], Nov. 3, 1851; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Peale, Harriet Cany, ca. 1800-1869
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Concerning the Peale family and Rembrandt.
  - Letter to Anna [Sellers], Nov. 5, 1851; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 4p. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], Dec. 15, 1851; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter. Business.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth [Sellers] Hill [Huddleson], Dec. 17, 1851; 6-1/4x4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Ellen [Eleanor Peale Sellers], Dec. 21-22, 1851; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905 (Box 13)
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 3, 1852; 10-3/4x8-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827 (Box 13)
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Describes his new house.
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, Jan. 12, 1852; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
  - Letter to Seyfert and McManus Company, Jan. 19, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning railroad parts shipped to him for the Panama Rail Road Company.
  - Letter to Titian R. Peale, Feb. 10, 1852; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.and 3p.additional material. Various sizes. (see Peale papers. No.10) Are of no relation to the De Peyster in the spoilation claims.
  - Letter to Mrs. A. Aims, Feb. 12, 1852; 7 1/4" x 9"; Bacon, Elizabeth
    Chester [England] A.L.S. 4p. and env. Presented by C.C. Sellers, June 1951.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Hannah Sellers Hill], March 7, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], March 14, 1852; 8-3/4x6-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Edward Bancroft, March 19, 1852; 12-1/2x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], March 21, 1852; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Mrs. [Hannah Sellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, March 23, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
  - Letter to Titian R. Peale, March 28, 1852; 10x8; Peale, Franklin, 1795-1870
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale papers. No. 10.) Makes a negative report on Titian Jr.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Cincinnati, April 5, 1852; 10x8; Whetstone, John L.
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p.and add.,end. (see peale-Sellers papers.) Business letter for patents and railroads.
  - Letter to [Ann Sellers], April 9, 1852; 12x7-1/2; Sellers, Nathan, 1788-1867
    a.L. 1p.with 2p., in pencil, of poems. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Ellen [Eleanor] P[eale] Sellers, Cincinnati, April 20, 1852; 7x4-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 4p.and end. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], May 5, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Price, William
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of his family and sick wife.
  - Letter to Ellen [Eleanor Peale Sellers], May 20, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to [Mrs. Hannah Sellers Hill], May 23, 1852; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], May 30, 1852; 8-3/4x6-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p.with P.S.by Cora Wells Sellers. Family news. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, June 21, 1852; 10x8; Hoadley, J. C. (John Chipman), 1818-1886
    Lawrence, Mass., 3p. A.L.S. Concerning locomotives. vol IIIp. 73
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, June 27, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], June 29, 1852; 9-1/2x8; Simpson, Charlotte Harrold
    A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. vol III p. 74
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], June 30, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and P.S.by Cora Sellers. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Anna Sellers, July 2, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
  - Letter to Cora [Mrs. Cornelia Wells Sellers], July 18, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], July 21, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p.with P.S.by Coleman Sellers. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [Anna Sellers], July 25, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p. Family news.
  - Letter to Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers, July 25, 1852; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], July 25, 1852; 10x8; Sellers, George Escol
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, Cincinnati, Aug. 2, 1852; 10x8; Foote, John P. (John Parsons), 1783-1865
    Washington, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning railroad development in the U.S.
  - Letter to Mrs. Hannah S[ellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, Aug. 4, 1852; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L. 2p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], Aug. 8, 1852; 9x7; Sellers, Harvey Lewis, 1813-1892
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of troubles with his wife.
  - Letter to Anna [Sellers], Aug. 28, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p.with P.S.by Coleman Sellers. Friendly letter.
  - Invitation to Peter Hill to attend the funeral of Sallie K. Crozer, Aug. 30, 1852; Unidentified
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, New York, Sept. 2, 1852; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Whetstone, John L.
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Terms for business agreement.
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, New York, Sept. 5, 1852; 11x8-1/2; Price, William R.
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p.and and.,end. Business. vol III p.77
  - Letter to [Coleman and Cornelia Wells Sellers], Sept. 12, 1852; 10x8; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p.and add.,end.and P.S.by Anna Sellers. Family news. Concerning the birth of Coleman.
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Philadelphia, Sept. 25, 1852; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Rachel, Sept. 26, 1852; Peale, Rembrandt, 1778-1860
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Oct. 3, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], Oct. 10, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.with P.S.by Anna to Rachel Sellers. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Oct. 24, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], Oct. 24, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], Oct. 30, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Nov. 6, 1852; 8-3/4x7; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Nov. 7, 1852; 10x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to George E[scol] Sellers, Nov. 10, 1852; 10x7-3/4; American Society of Civil Engineers
    New York, Printed L.filled in in ms. 1p. Norifies him of election to membership. Vol IIIp.81
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, Nov. 18, 1852; 10-1/4x8; Aylmer, John Tucker(?)
    A.L.S. 6p.with P.S.by Ellen Jane Aylmer, and add. Friendly letter. volIIIp.81
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 5, 6, 1852; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 6, 1852; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
  - Letter to [Mrs] Eliz[abeth Sellers Hill Huddleson], Dec. 11, 1852; 9x8; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], Dec. 12, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Eleanor P[eale] Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 19, 1852; 8-1/2x7; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Mrs. Elizabeth Sellers Hill Huddleson?], 1852?; 8x6-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, [ca.]. A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Cornelia Wells] Sellers, [1852?]; 5-1/4x4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859 (Box 13)
    A.L. 2p.and add.with envelope end.concerning Charles Sellers. Mutilated. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Jan. 2, 1853; 10x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827 (Box 14)
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, Cincinnati, Jan. 5, 1853; 10x8, 8x5; Aylmer, John F.
    Dublin, A.L.S. 8p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning his son in America and their Kindness to him.
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], Jan. 7, 9, [1853?]; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], Jan. 16, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 16, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill [Huddleson], Jan. 16, 1853; 9x8; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Marion, Ohio, A.L.S.: Sophy. 4p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Enjoys living in Ohio.
  - Letter to [Eleanor P. Sellers], Jan. 18, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Frederick Harrold, 1834-
    Aurora, A.L.S. 2p. (See Peale-Sellers papers.) Does not like working on railroads.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Hannah Sellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, Jan. 23, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Family news.
  - Letter to [Eleanor Peale Sellers], Jan. 30, 1853; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Aylmer, Gerald George
    A.L.S.in poetic form. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, Jan. 30, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Family news.
  - Letter to [Ann Sellers], Feb. 5, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Nathan, 1788-1867
    A.L. 1p.and end. Concerning the sale of his estate.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Feb. 13, 1853; 10x8; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and P.S.by Coleman Sellers of 2p. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Hannah Sellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, Feb. 20, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Feb. 27, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Feb. 27, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], March 13, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to J. & D. De Camp, March 15, 1853; 3-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 1p.with receipt signed by George Warner on the reverse. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Asks them to pay George Warner for him.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], March 20, 1853; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p. Family news. Business.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, March 27, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p.,add.with P.S.by Anna Sellers Friendly letter.
  - Invitation to Ann Sellers to attend the funeral of George Sellers, April 7, 1853; Unidentified
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, April 8, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Concerning the death of Uncle George. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Hannah Sellers] Hill, Pennsgrove, April 9, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 1p.and add. Concerning the death of George Sellers.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], April 10, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], April 17, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to G[eorge] E[scol] Sellers, Cleveland, April 22, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Eleanor Peale
    Cincinnati, L.S.: Ellie P., Lucy, Harry, and "your ever affectionate wife [Mrs. Rachel Brooks Parrish Sellers]. 4p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Family news.
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], April 24, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to [Mrs. Elizabeth Sellers Hill Huddleson], May 8, 1853; 7-1/2x6-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Marion, Ohio, A.L.S.: Sophie, 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of her life in Ohio.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, May 9, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, May 15, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Family news. Business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], May 22, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], May 26, 1853; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Harrold, Fanny (Frances Elizabeth)
    A.L.S. 2p. Mutilated. Friendly letter. vol III p. 91
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, June 11, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers], June 12, 1853; 10x8; Sellers, Rachel Brooks Parrish
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], June 12, 1853; 8-1/2x7; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and P.S.by Anna Sellers. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [Horatio Allen], June 15, 1853; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, George Escol
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.,end. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning purchasing into a machine shop.
  - Letter to Mrs. [Sophonisba Peale] Sellers, Philadelphia, June 19, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Family news.
  - Letter to Horatio Allen, June 26, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning purchasing into a machine shop.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] E[scol] Sellers, June 30, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Allen, Horatio, 1802-1889
    New York, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.)
  - Letter to [Horatio Allen], July 4, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, George Escol
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p.,end. Draft. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Machinery business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Cornelia Wells Sellers], July 5, 1853; 12x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, July 7, 1853; 10x8; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Marion, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], July 10, 1853; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Anna [Sellers], Aug. 2, 1853; 10x8; Pendleton, Charlotte Ramsay Robinson, 1819-1886
    A.L.S. 3P. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) News of her mother.
  - Letter to Anna Sellers, Aug. 18, 1853; 7x4-1/2; Pendleton, David
    Martinsburg, A.L.S. 1p. Friendly letter. vol III p 94
  - Letter to Ellen [Eleanor Peale Sellers], Aug. 21, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], Aug. 28, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L. 1p.with P.S.of 3p.by Anna Sellers. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Charles [W. Peale, Aug. 30, 1853; 8x5; Peale, Rubens, 1784-1865
    Woodland, A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) Concerning life at home. Wants to know of the business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Hannah Sellers Hill;]., Aug., 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Ann, b. 1785
    A.L. 2p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth [Sellers] Hill [Huddleson], Philadelphia, Sept. 6, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Mrs. C. W. [Harriet] Peale, Shamokin, Sept. 21, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Friel, P.
    Cornwall, A.L. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale papers. Mills collection.) News of relatives and friends in Lebanon.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Sept. 25, 1853; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Eleanor P. Sellers], Nov. 1, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Frederick Harrold, 1834-
    Aurora, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Shippen papers.) News of life in Indiana.
  - Letter to Mrs. C. W. [Harriet] Peale, Shamokin, Nov. 2, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Friel, P.
    Lebanon, A.L. 3p.and add.,end. (see Peale Papers. Mills collection.) News of friends in Lebanon.
  - Letter to [George Escol] Sellers, Nov. 9, 1853; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883
    A.L.S. 2p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Exploring for a railroad.
  - Letter to George Escol Sellers, Cincinnati, Nov. 13, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Anna [Sellers], Nov. 14, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Augusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Ann Sellers, Philadelphia, Nov. 22, 1853; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    New York, A.L.S. 3p.and add. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Eleanor Peale Sellers], Nov. 28, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Frederick Harrold, 1834-
    Aurora, A.L.S. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Has little news. Hopes they visit in Aurora.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 11, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 18, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Dec. 18, 1853; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Dec. 25, 1853; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to Geo[rge] E[scol] Sellers, Dec. 27, 1853; 10-1/2x8; Ely, Alfred B. (Alfred Brewster), 1817-1872
    Boston, A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers;], 1853; 8x6-1/2; Pendleton, Charlotte Ramsay Robinson, 1819-1886
    ca. A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Misses her mother.
  - Letter to Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers, [ca. 1853-1854]; Pendleton, Charlotte Ramsay Robinson, 1819-1886
  - Letter to [Coleman Sellers], Jan. 1, 1854; 8x6-1/2; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Jan. 1, 1854; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Jan. 2, 1854; 9-3/4x7-1/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Ella [Eleanor] P. Sellers, Cincinnati, Jan. 6, 1854; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Frederick Harrold, 1834-
    Aurora, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Could not write before, since the river was closed. Is well.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Jan. 22, 1854; 9-3/4x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Feb. 5, 1854; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning little Coleman. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, Feb. 5, 1854; 9-1/2x7-1/2; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 3p.and add.,end. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Feb. 12, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to Cha[rle]s Sellers, Feb. 22, 1854; 8-1/4x5-1/4; Peale, Charles Willson, 1741-1827
    A.L.S. 1p.and end. Concerning a locomotive for heavy grades. Business.
  - Invitation to Peter Hill to attend the funeralof James Sellers, Jr., [Feb. 24, 1854]; Sellers, James, 1783-1857
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Feb. 26, 1854; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Invitation to Peter Hill to attend the funeralof James M. Wilcox., March 4, 1854; Unidentified
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers and Ann Sellers], March 6, 1854; 8-3/4x7-1/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Ann Sellers], March 19, 1854; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to G[eorge] Escol Sellers, New York, March 20, 1854; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Abert, John James, 1788-1863
    Washington, L.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Report on his orograph.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], March 24, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Coleman, b. 1827
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Elizabeth S[ellers] Hill [Huddleson], Pennsgrove, March 25, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Marion, A.L.S. 4p.,add. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Rubens Peale, March 26, 1854; 8x6-1/2; Stockton, Eliza Ferguson Peale, 1799-1876
    A.L.S. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers Papers.) Sorry about his leg, but hopes he will take this as a mark of God's blessings.
  - Letter to Coleman Sellers, Cincinnati, March 27, 1854; 7-1/4x5-3/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [George Escol] Sellers, March 29, 1854; 10x8; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883
    A.L.S. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Railroad business.
  - Letter to [George] Escol [Sellers], April 19, 1854; 6-1/2x5; Sellers, Rachel Brooks Parrish
    Cincinnati, A.L.S.: Chelly. 2p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Family news.
  - Letter to Geo[rge] Escol Sellers, April 27, 1854; 8x5; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883
    Philadelphia, L. 1p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) He will receive letter from the president of the railroad when the president returns.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Hannah Sellers Hill], May 8, 1854; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Huddleson, Elizabeth Sellers Hill
    A.L. 4p. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Has been so busy cleaning house and helping at Mill Bank. Wishes to see her.
  - Letter to O. M. Mitchell, June 9, 1854; 9-3/4x8; Bache, A. D. (Alexander Dallas), 1806-1867
    Wilmington, A.L.S. 2p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Concerning G.E.Sellers orograph.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], June 16, 1854; 10x7-3/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Anna [Sellers], July 8, 1854; 10x7-3/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 4p. Mutilated. Friendly letter. Family news.
  - Letter to Mrs. Sophonisba [Peale] Sellers, Cincinnati, July 9, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Sophy [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Peale], July 21, 1854; 7-1/4x5-3/4; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to Coleman [Sellers], July 24, Aug. 4, 1854; 10x8; Price, James M. (James Martin), 1825-1899
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. vol IVp. 7
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Angusciola Peale Sellers], July 26, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Charles, 1806-1898
    Marion, A.L.S. 1p.and end. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Are well, but think his child should come home.
  - Letter to [George Escol] Sellers, July 26, 1854; 7x4-1/2; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p.,end.: "Written soon after the loss of his right hand..." In pencil (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Is well. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Coleman and Cor[neli]a [Wells] Sellers, Cincinnati, July 30, 1854; 8-3/4x7-1/4; Peale, Sophonisba Angusciola, 1786-1859
    Marion, A.L.S. 4p.and add. Friendly letter. Concerning the cholera.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Aug. 6, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    Mill Bank, A.L.S. 4p. Friendly letter. Family news. Refers to Espy.
  - Letter to Anna [Sellers], Aug. 21, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Cornelia Wells, 1831-1909
    Cincinnati, A.L.S. 2p. Friendly letter. Concerning Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers.
  - Letter to [George Escol] Sellers, Aug. 22, 1854; 8-1/2x5; Trautwine, John C. (John Cresson), 1810-1883
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. In pencil. (see Peale-Sellers papers.) Railroad business.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers], Aug. 27, 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
  - Letter to [Mrs. Sophonisba Peale Sellers?, Aug., 1854; 10x8; Sellers, Anna, 1824-1905
    ca.]. A.L. 2p. Fragment. Friendly letter. Refers to Espy.
  - Letter to Ellie and Lucy, Sept. 1, 1854; "Eliza"